

lichendi.cs@gmail.com

looking for a 2022 Fall Ph.D. program

Personal website

I am currently a graduate student at the State Key Laboratory of Computer Architecture, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, supervised by Prof. **Yunquan Zhang**. My research interests including high-performance computing, sparse/dense matrix multiplication and AI+HPC. The expected graduation date is 2022 Summer.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences **Bachelor of Computer Science,** Hunan Agricultural University

Sep 2019 — June 2022

Sep 2014 — June 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Research Assistant

Sep 2019 — Present

State Key Laboratory of Computer Architecture, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Jan 2018 — June 2019

State Key Laboratory of Computer Architecture, Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. [IEEE ISPA 2021] Chendi Li, Haipeng Jia, Hang Cao, et al. AutoTSMM: An Auto-tuning Framework for Building High-Performance Tall-and-Skinny Matrix-Matrix Multiplication on CPUs.
- 2. [IEEE ICPADS 2021, accepted] Jianyu Yao, Boqian Shi, Chunyang Xiang, Haipeng Jia, Chendi Li, et al. IAAT: An Input-Aware Adaptive Tuning framework for Small GEMM.
- 3. [IEEE HPCC 2021, accepted] Tun Chen, Haipeng Jia, Zhihao Li, Chendi Li, et al. A Transpose-free Three-dimensional FFT Algorithm on ARM CPUs
- 4. [CCF HPC China 2020] Chendi Li, Guangting Zhang, Haipeng Jia. Fast Computation of Elementary Functions on ARM Platforms(in Chinese)

RESEARCH PROJECTS

AutoTSMM, Author

Nov 2020 — Present

• Designed AutoTSMM, which is used to build high-Performance tall-and-skinny matrix multiplication on all mainstream CPUs. AutoTSMM can speed up convolution layers in real-world deep learning applications, and the performance is competitive with Intel OneMKL and outperforms all conventional GEMM implementationss. This work is published in IEEE ISPA 2021.

OpenBLAS, Contributor

Nov 2020 — Present

• Optimized pre-pack matrix-matrix multiplication and triangular solve with multiple right-hand-sides(TRSM) on ARMv8 and X86 platforms. OpenBLAS is a one of the most famous open-source BLAS library.

IAAT, Contributor

Nov 2020 — Present

• Launched the project and investigated JIT tools for small GEMM. IAAT is a template-driven just-in-time(JIT) small GEMM framework targeting CPUs. This work is accepted by IEEE ICPADS 2021.

OpenVML, Co-author

Jan 2020 — Oct 2020

• Optimized the math functions on the ARMv8 platform. OpenVML is a vector math library. It achieves an outstanding performance improvement compared to C standard library and ARMPL. This work is accepted by HPC China 2020.

AutoFFT, Contributor

Jan 2018 — Present

• Optimized small-scale FFT on ARMv8 platforms, and did some works on multi-threading and 2D-FFT. AutoFFT is a template-based FFT codes auto-generation framework for ARM and X86 CPUs. This work is published in SC'19 and TPDS'20.

AWARDS & HONORS

2021	First	:-class	schol	arsh	ips
	_				

2020 Second-class scholarship

2019 Third-class scholarship, Outstanding intern in PerfXLab

2015 Collegiate programming contest first prize; Outstanding volunteer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools Linux, Git, Vim, CMake, GDB, OpenMP, Pthreads **Programming/Scripting** C, Latex, Assembly, Python, Neon intrinsic